OBJECTIVE

I want to deliver a strong message, through making real changes aimed towards improving and making the place we live in better. A place that allows people to have an obstacle-free path that allows unlimited growth. Therefore, I will dedicate my passion and ambition for problem-solving, analytical skills, and my various and extremely competent Software Engineering expertise in multiple fields to achieve this goal.

EDUCATION

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals (KFUPM)

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Sep 2016 - May 2021

Georgia Institute of Technology (GT)

Exchange Program, Computer Science

Atlanta, GA, United States

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

EXPERIENCE

Axenda Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Mar 2020 - Present Founder & Leader

- Working with a team of 2-90 people, lead/manage when needed.
- o Working on products' structure, design, and implementation.

Sary Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Product Intern / Business Analyst

Mar 2020 - Jul 2020

Analyzing product processes for optimization while also identifying problems for solutions

Udacity Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

iOS Session Lead

Mar 2019 - Aug 2020

- Explaining iOS nanodegree concepts through weekly meeting with students
- Setting up a Slack channel and frequently communicating with students on Slack

TechBench Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Member / Technical Lead

Oct 2018 - Aug 2020

- Introducing tech to people by conducting workshops, and hackathons
- Leading the development of Enigma and other projects

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals (KFUPM)

Database Systems Grader

o Assisting course professor & grading assignments

Feb 2020 - May 2020 Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Intro to Computing Grader

iOS Developer

- o Advanced my skills in OOP programming, specifically, with Java
- Wrote JavaScript scripts to automate some of the grading tasks

Tweetso

Developed two native iOS applications (Experto, and Experto Provider)

- Worked with Firebase services such as Authentication and Databases

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Nov 2017 - Jul 2018

PROJECTS

El Jabal (Swift, Firebase, Python, and JavaScript)

Mar 2018 - Mar 2020

- An iOS application that serves students at KFUPM (Not official)
- o Helps students to make a full graduation plan
- Gives the ability to browse KFUPM's course offerings

Enigma (Nginx, PM2, Node.js, Vue.js, and PostgreSQL)

Feb 2019 - Mar 2019

- o A programming contest control system
- Used in TechBench's HackDay which was sponsored by Saudi Aramco and Information & Computer Science department at KFUPM
- Team work

AWARDS

Wa'ed Hackathon at Dhahran Techno Valley (DTV) and Ithra

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

First Place, Recreational Activities Challenge

Dec 2018

SAP Hackathon at King Abdullah University of Science and Technology (KAUST)

Thuwal, Saudi Arabia

Top Three, Smart Parking Challenge

Feb 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Udacity

Front End Web Developer Nanodegree	Apr 2019
Full Stack Web Developer Nanodegree	Dec 2018
iOS Developer Nanodegree	Nov 2018

VOLUNTEERISM

KFUPM Voluntary Work Unit

Volunteer Assistant

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Feb 2018, 2019, 2020

Participated in the annual volunteering day at KFUPM for three years
Worked with people from different backgrounds

Microsoft

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Dec 2017

- Worked together along with Microsoft engineers
- o Introduced Microsoft's micro-computer 'micro:bit' to children on a workshop

Code.org

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Trainer

Trainer

- Worked together along with 12 other volunteers from KFUPM
- Introduced Code.org to 402 children throughout several workshops

Dec 2017

REFERENCES

Database Systems Assistant Professor, KFUPM Salah Adam

adam@kfupm.edu.sa

iOS Course Manager, Udacity Dania Abedaljawad

dania.abedaljawad@udacity.com